准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
白水母记
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
分镜指导
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
白水母记
欢迎各位聆听多比迪克的惊险传奇
Welcome to the terrific, tumultuous tale of Dopey Dick
叫我鱼实玛利
Call me Fishmael
我年轻时
In my youth
曾是一位青春无畏的出道学徒工
I was an intrepid, fresh-faced journeyman
行进在各个城市间  寻找工作
looking from town to town for any work I could find
那时我并不知道  我将要踏上
Little did I know, I was about to step in some
水母酱
Jellyfish jelly?
大水母客店
欢迎光临大水母客店
Welcome to the Jelly Squirt Inn
需要什么服务  老兄
How can we help, me hearty?
不好意思
Excuse me
要不要喝水母汁  小子
Have some jelly juice, lad?
不用了
No, thanks
我在找工作
I'm job hunting
敢问你们有没有什么工作
Might you lubbers have employment
可以让拥有收银经验的
for an able-legged young buck
双腿健全年轻人负责的
with cash register experience?
没有
No, no
只有我才能碰我的钱
Nobody touches me money but me
要么买水母酱  要么滚出去
Buy some jelly, or get out
拿去
Here you go
过来
Come here
兄弟
Hey, buddy
我听说
I've heard tell
有艘叫老菠萝的船
that a boat called "Ye Olde Pineapple"
马上要出航了
is shipping out soon
需要多招水手
and they need more hands
你手就挺多的
You've got plenty of hands
我好像听到他们切船的声音了
I think I hear them cutting the ship right now
谢谢  不过我晕船
Thanks, but I always get seasick
我绝对不会上船的
I wouldn't be caught dead on a ship
这种话让我倍感遗憾
I'm so sorry to hear that
抓到了
Got one
天啊
Egads
我被绑架了
I've been squid-napped
没错
Yup
船长有份特别的工作要给你
The captain has a special job just for ye
要给我
For me?
不对  给你
No, for ye
我确实挺需要工作
Well, I do need a job
反正晕船就晕船吧
If I get seasick, I get seasick
放心好了
Don't worry
我来让你熟悉门道
I'll show ye the ropes
绳 子
有大绳子
There's the big rope
小绳子
the little rope
苦瓜脸绳子
the frowny rope
笑脸绳子
the smiley rope
还有甘草绳子
and the licorice rope
这个是我的
This one's mine
你会打结吗
Do you know how to tie a knot?
不会  不过我愿意学
No, but I'd love to learn
我会教你的
I'll teach ya
之后
果不其然
Typical
停住
Avast ye
我是海绵亚哈船长
I be Captain Sponge-Hab
我带你们来  是要执行特别任务
I brought you all here for a special mission--
猎捕巨大白水母
to hunt down the great white jellyfish
多比迪克
Dopey Dick
多比迪克就是那只
Was Dopey Dick the beast
夺去你的腿的野兽吗  船长
who took off thy leg, Captain?
才不是
Naw
我的腿都挤进锅铲柄了
My leg is all squeezed into the handle
我只是爱听我锅铲碰地的声音
I just love the sound my spatula makes
多比迪克是一只巨大白水母
Dopey Dick is a great white jellyfish, lads
大小有如一间分层套房
And he's the size of a split-level condominium
好多水母酱
All that jelly
大家好好寻找多比迪克
So keep your eyes peeled for Dopey Dick
如果找到了就大声通知我
And if ye spot him, just give me a holler
对  就那样
Yes, just like that
看到的话就应该是这种反应
That is exactly what you should do
when you actually see him
多比迪克
Dopey Dick
水母就是笨
Jellyfish be dumb
追上那座雪山
Chase that snow-hilled hump
你  戴着漂亮羊毛帽的
You, in the smart wool cap
有份特殊活儿要让你干
I have a special job for ye
我准备好了
I be ready
什么活
What is it?
这就是特殊活儿吗
This is the special job?
你来当黏性鱼叉枪刚刚好
You'll make a great sticky harpoon
发射
Fire
好吧  我现在要吐了
Okay, now I'm gonna throw up
我们抓到了
We got him
我们被抓到了
He's got us
慢一点吧  多比迪克
Please slow down, Dopey Dick
我都没什么好吐的了
I don't have anything left to throw up
等等  我知道怎么抚慰凶猛的野兽
Wait, I know how to soothe a savage beast
我耳朵在咬我
My ears are biting me
多比迪克抵抗不了音乐的吸引力
Dopey Dick cannot resist the music
大家动作快  收绳子
Quick, everyone, reel him in
现在  各位兄弟
Now, me hearties
来到了猎捕水母最好的一部分
comes the best part of hunting down
and catching a jellyfish
抹水母酱
Spreading the jelly
好  好
Yeah, yeah
不对  笨蛋
No, you sillies
是要放了水母
Releasing the jellyfish
飞离这里吧  多比迪克
Fly and be free, Dopey Dick
你们好
Ahoy, mateys
抓得好啊
Nice catch
现在该你们放了
Now it's your turn to release him
我们才不会放
We're not releasing bupkis
抱歉  船长
I'm sorry, Cap'n
恐怕我们要留着多比迪克
I'm afraid we're just gonna keep Dopey Dick
卖它的水母酱了
and sell his jelly for money
钱  钱
Money, money
他怎么能肆意压榨
How can he exploit
如此稀有又温驯的生物
such a rare and gentle creature?
多比迪克是我们的朋友
Dopey Dick is our friend
要是你们以为能乘虚而入
And if ye think you're just gonna swoop in here
把我们朋友关进笼子
and put our friend in a cage
那你们麻烦就大了
ye've got another thing coming
对吧  忠诚船员们
Right, me loyal crew?
太震惊了
Shiver me timbers
好一个反向叛变
It's a reverse mutiny
假胡子
Fake-Beard
带这个上甲板吧
Put this in your poop deck
你这是哑炮
Ye cannonball is a dud
等着瞧
Wait for it
饿
Hungry
线虫
Nematodes
必须从那群海盗手里救回多比迪克
We've got to save Dopey Dick
from them pilfering pirates
需要更大的菠萝
We're gonna need a bigger pineapple
你想多了
Scupper that
派巴克  跟上那群舱底的老鼠
Pat-Buck, follow those bilge rats
遵命  海绵亚哈船长
Aye, aye, Captain Sponge-Hab
多比
Dopey
肚子安静
Quiet, stomach
会吵醒大家的
You'll wake everybody
大家跟我来
Follow me, me hearties
谁在那
Who's there?
是你啊  亲爱的
It's you, honey
好险啊
That was close
抱歉
Sorry
水母酱
坐好了  多比
Sit tight, Dopey
我们会帮你解开的
We're gonna cut you loose
再电下去就救不出来了
Not if he keeps doing that, we won't
你走吧
There you go
自由了  多比
All free, Dopey
捉水母多美好啊
Ain't jellyfishing wonderful?
有人欠了我三百吨水母酱
Somebody owes me 300 tons of jellyfish jelly
不知道章鱼有没有酱
I wonder if octopuses give jelly
真有吗
Do they?
没有
No
好心人  你收欠条吗
Kind sir, will ye take an IOU?
我要扒下你的一只眼
I'll take an eye
或者两只
or two
大家听见没
Do ye hear it, lads?
听见没
Do ya?
多比迪克的歌
Dopey Dick's song
我们还有机会能捉到
We still have a chance to catch him
所有人进入战斗岗位
Everyone, beat to quarters
吃鱼叉枪吧  傻蛋
Hardy har-poon, sucker
多比  不要
Dopey, no
帮我解开  你个笨蛋
Cut me loose, you Dopey dunce
为了心头的仇恨
For hate's sake
我们要和你拼到最后一息
we spit our last breath at thee
海绵亚哈船长
Captain Sponge-Hab
我再也不想在这工作了
I don't wanna work here anymore
于是我成为了
And that's how I became
多比迪克猎捕过程中唯一的幸存者
the sole survivor of the hunt for Dopey Dick
你才不是唯一的幸存者
You weren't the sole survivor
大家都还在呢
We were all there
这是我的故事
It's my story
我才是主角
I'm the hero
我想怎么结局就怎么结局
And I can end it any way I want
鱼实玛利啊
Fishmael
给大家再请一份水母汁
You're all buying another round of jelly juice
那群得坏血病的猪头
Those scurvy swine
就是不懂什么故事才算好
wouldn't know a good story
但凡吃点苦
if it bit them on the--
讲完了
The end
痞老板与魔豆
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
在很久以前
Once upon a time
有一只幼稚的小浮游生物  名叫杰克
there lived a naive little plankton named Jack
杰克的海霸农场干枯了
Jack's Chum Farm had dried up
而且身上还只剩一法寻
and he only had one single farthing left
[ 法寻：货币单位，4法寻合1便士 ]
去市场买食物的钱
to buy food at the market
不用怕  凯伦
Fear not, Karen
我的钟表老婆
my clockwork wife
我会好好花这最后一法寻
I will spend our last farthing wisely
让咱俩免受饥饿之苦
and save us from starvation
马上发财
魔豆只要一法寻
Get rich now?
魔豆
Magic bean?
只要一法寻
Only one farthing?
赚大钱
Ka-ching
凯伦
Oh, Karen
我中大奖了
I hit the jackpot
感恩海神王
Thank King Neptune
你赚到食物和清漆了吗
Did you get plenty of food and varnish?
比那强
Better than that
我有魔豆了
I got a magical bean
什么
What?
怎么处理  煮了吗
What do you do, boil it?
不是用来吃的
You don't eat it
是魔力
It's magic
杰克啊  你居然用咱最后一点钱
Oh, Jack, I can't believe you blew our last penny
浪费在一颗破豆子上
on a stupid bean
虽然我还需要清漆
I still need varnish
但是我不会让你挨饿的
but I'm not gonna let you go hungry
嘴巴张开
Open wide
跟你说魔豆不是用来吃的
I told you, you don't eat it
是
It's--
我饱了
Well, I'm full
跟你说吧  凯伦
I told you so, Karen
又来了
There he goes--
为了吵赢无所不用其极
anything to win an argument
会不会强健心脏我不管
I don't care if they are good for my heart
反正我再也不吃豆子了
I am never eating another bean
老蟹堡王
"Ye Old Krusty Krab"?
也许里面有人可以帮我发大财
Maybe someone there can make me rich
好像有人快噎死了
Sounds like someone is choking to death
你放心
Don't worry
我来救你了
I'll save you
鹅跑过来了
Galloping goose flesh
我是出于好意  凯伦
I meant well, Karen
看准了再啄
Watch where you're pecking
你个鸟毛怪物
you foul-feathered freak
什么
What the--
我闻到了地上凡人的血味
I smell the blood of a Bottomite
原来是你  海绵大鹅
It's just you, SpongeGoose
不能再喂你吃凡人食物了
I have to stop feeding you people food
大鹅乖
Be a good goose
给我下点蟹黄堡
and lay some Krabby Patties on me
魔法竖琴  奏乐
Magic harp, do your thing
好难听
Horrible
准备好了
It's ready
可以吃的金子
Edible gold
我发财了
I'm rich
谢了  魔豆
Thank you, magic bean
我这就要开吃
Don't mind if I do
谁胆敢侵犯我的一方净土
Who disturbs me inner sanctum?
今天天气好差啊
Crazy weather, huh?
逮到了
Got ya
不管你到底有没有被关着
Whether you're caged or whether you're loose
都得给我去喂我黄金大鹅
I'll feed you to me golden goose
不行  别让我喂鹅
No, not the goose
不要
No
马上就能有黄金小不点了
I'll have a solid gold pipsqueak
大概要四个小时
in about four hours
躲猫猫
Peekaboo
什么
What?
快点跑  跑过来的大鹅
Giddy up, galloping goose flesh
弃鹅逃命
Abandon goose
我都忘了鹅会飞
I forgot geese can fly
行  不讲童话故事了
All right, enough of this storybook stuff
来打激光枪
It's laser time, baby
树倒了
Timber
好  大鹅你留着吧
Okay, you can keep the goose
完蛋
Oh, no
凯伦
Karen
杰克  看你对我们家干的好事
Jack, look what you did to our house
我刚为你灭了个巨人
I just slayed a giant for you
能别批我了吗
You want to lay off?
之后
黄金堡
快来看魔鹅跳舞
好吃
Delicious
拿去
There you go
用餐愉快  先生
Bon appétit, sir
你说得对  亲爱的
You were right, darling
魔豆确实有魔力
That bean was magic
请问你在这神奇的一天要买什么
And what can I get for you on this magical day
我的好先生
my good sir?
请来一份双层黄金堡套餐
I'd like a double gold patty combo, please
不穿衣服不穿鞋
No shirt, no shoes
身上没壳  不提供服务
no shell, no service
滚吧  小不点
Take a hike, tiny